Luke Rymarz

Software Engineer

574 N 19th St San Jose, CA 95112

(408) 636-6230 LukeRymarz@gmail.com www.LukeRymarz.com

9 years experience designing and developing web applications in HTML/JavaScript/CSS and Flex/ActionScript/Flash. 9 years experience with C and C++ applications. Also comfortable with C# and Java.

Deep-seated passion for video games.

Hobby applications include a website for browsing animated gifs, a Stack Overflow clone, a Facebook application for browsing friends' photos, and a Dungeons and Dragons character builder.

Experience

Software Engineer

March 2010 – Present

San Jose, CA



Adobe Systems, Inc. www.adobe.com

- Experience with Agile (Scrum) and Lean (Kanban) software development methodologies.
- Developed software in local and remote teams.
- Contributing member of the AdobeRevel.com web development team. Technologies used include Ruby on Rails, nginx, HTML5, HAML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Amazon Web Services.
- Worked with seven engineers to build a Ruby-on-Rails based website for browsing and purchasing third party Creative Suite extensions (AdobeExchange.com).
- Developed Extension Builder 2, an Eclipse-based IDE for building Creative Suite Extensions.
- Worked in a small team to build Customs House, a tool for managing export compliance documents for all Adobe products. Written in Adobe Flex.



Software Engineer

August 2004 – March 2010

Harmonic, Inc. (previously Omneon) www.harmonicinc.com San Jose, CA

- Worked in a team of approximately 10 on MAS, a video asset management system.
 Responsibilities included
 - Design and implementation of search interface and other elements of the UI in Adobe Flex.
 - Design and implementation of a QuickTime-based player in JavaScript and Adobe Flex (ExternalInterface).
- Independently designed and developed various Omneon products in accordance with marketing and engineering requirements, including
 - ProBrowse Desktop, a PostgreSQL database driven video explorer and player written in C++ with MFC and DirectShow.
 - EDLTool, a complimentary application to ProBrowse Desktop allowing cuts-only video editing
 of proxies created by the ProBrowse system. Written in C++ with MFC, Windows Forms, and
 DirectShow.
 - ContentManager, a C# application which adds administrative capabilities to Omneon MediaGrid
 using remote procedure calls and interaction with Active Directory domain controllers.
- Maintained and extended MediaTools, a broad array of C++/MFC applications supporting functionality of Omneon Spectrum servers.
- Other experience includes: InstallShield, CVS, Subversion, Mercurial, FTP, HTML, CSS, Cygwin, Perl, PHP, Apache, JavaScript, QuickTime, GIMP, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Flash/Flex Builder, Flash Catalyst, Flash Professional.

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

August 2001 – May 2004

Washington State University

Pullman, WA

Hobbies

Photography, Video Games, Rock Climbing, Single Malt Scotch, Soap-making